Daniel G. Phillips

20455 1st Ave NE Apt. H104, Poulsbo, WA 98370 (720) 378-3770 phillips-6b01381b0/

danielphillips0101@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/daniel-

Professional Summary

Self-motivated, exceptional supervisor of personnel, and worker as a Nuclear Machinist Mate, through eleven years of Naval Service. Completed two years of Navy school for Nuclear Engineering, six years on board two aircraft carriers operating and maintaining a nuclear propulsion plant, and three years as a Quality Assurance Inspector inspecting critical submarine maintenance.

Skills

- **Power Plant Supervision**
- **Quality Assurance**
- **Project Management and Coordination**
- Nuclear Maintenance Planning and Execution
- Team Leadership, Mentoring, and Coaching

- Personnel Management
- Mechanical Component Design
- **Nuclear Power Plant Operations**
- Heavy Machinery Operation and Repair
- Secret Security Clearance

Experience

Reactor Propulsion Leading Petty Officer

June 2019 - July 2020; USS Carl Vinson, Bremerton, WA

- Manage seven divisional leaders and 122 sailors through daily operations
- Supervise ten Technical Program Managers
- Implemented new programs to streamline administrative processes and reduced audit deficiencies

Quality Assurance Inspector

October 2016 - June 2019; Trident Refit Facility, Bangor, WA

- Performed quality assurance inspections for controlled work and critically coated surface areas
- Obtained SSPC (NBPI) Paint Inspector certification
- Reviewed technical work packages for accuracy and relevance

Maintenance Group Supervisor

June 2011 - June 2016; USS Theodore Roosevelt, Norfolk, VA

- Coordinated and planned corrective maintenance for Reactor Mechanical Division
- Coordinated and planned the execution of Board of Inspection and Survey (INSURV) forty demonstrations, resulting in the successful completion of the inspection; Specifically cited by the INSURV team's report for efforts and level of knowledge
- Operated a nuclear steam plant to produce propulsion and electricity for the ship
- Critical supervisory watchstander for multiple successful Operational Reactor Safeguard Examinations
- Oversaw and completed numerous complex maintenance items on pumps, turbines, generators, gearboxes, air compressors,
- Extensive experience in controlled work completion and documentation.

Qualified Chief Reactor Watch, Reactor Mechanical Operator, Primary Valve Operator, Work Center Supervisor

Professional Education

Machinist Mate Nuclear

July 2009 - November 2010; Naval Nuclear Power Training Command, Goose Creek, SC

The training covered atomic and nuclear physics, heat transfer, fluid flow, chemistry, technical mathematics, nuclear design theory, mechanical systems, electricity basics, industrial safety, radiation physiology, and power plant theory.

Nuclear Power Plant Operator

November 2010 - June 2011; Naval Nuclear Power Training Unit, Goose Creek, SC

The training covered communications, qualification process, physics, mechanical/electrical systems, and nuclear power plant operations.

Steam Plant Maintenance Supervisor

June 2016 - September 2016; Surface Warfare Officer School, San Diego, CA

The course covered main/auxiliary turbine, steam generator (conventional), forced draft blower, machinery controller/governor/regulator, and air compressor (high and low pressure) maintenance.

Awards and Honors

National Defense Service Medal - 2009

Navy Achievement Medal - 2014

Good Conduct Medal - 2015

Global War on Terrorism Service Medal - 2015

Global War on Terrorism Expeditionary Medal - 2015

Sea Service Deployment Ribbon - 2015

Meritorious Unit Commendation - 2016

Good Conduct Medal - 2018

Naval Achievement Medal - 2019